<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Robot | KING]]></title>
  <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/categories/robot/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-06-02T16:38:55+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://pbking1.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[pb]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Basic Idea in Robotics]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2014/04/09/basic-idea-in-robotics/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-09T18:55:54+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2014/04/09/basic-idea-in-robotics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>ABSTRACT:</h3>

<ul>
<li>The basic idea in robotic area

<ul>
<li>A robot is an autonomous system which exists in the physical world, can sense its environment , and can act on it to achieve some goals</li>
<li>The robotic involves autonomy, sensing, action, and achieving goals, all in the physical world</li>
<li>The component of the robot are

<ul>
<li>physical body

<ul>
<li>it can exist and do in the physical world</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>combine

<ul>
<li>manipulation(up body)

<ul>
<li>handling objects</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>locomotion(down body).

<ul>
<li>Moving around, going places</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Sensors

<ul>
<li>It can sense/perceive its environment in order to get information about itself and its surroundings.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Effectors and actuators

<ul>
<li>it can take actions</li>
<li>effector enable a robot to take a action, to do physical things

<ul>
<li>it can also be defined as any device that has an effect on the environment</li>
<li>it range from legs, wheels to arms and fingers</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>actuator can do exact the actual work for the robot

<ul>
<li>are the effector that use underlying mechanism, such as motor and muscles.</li>
<li>Is also the mechanism that enable the effector to execute an action or movement</li>
<li>Such as electric motors(base on electric current), hydraulics(base on fluid pressure) ,pneumatics(base on air pressure) and photo-reactive materials ……</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>Controller

<ul>
<li>it can be autonomous</li>
<li>provide hardware and/or software that make the robot autonomous by using the sensor inputs and any other information to decide what to do ad then to control the effectors to execute that action</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<h3>Some useful info about ATLAS robot</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>1.ATLAS robot has 27 total degrees of freedom.</p></li>
<li><p>2.ATLAS has 27 powerful actuators. They are very strong.</p>

<ul>
<li>And they are using the Hydraulic Actuator</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>3.Even though ATLAS uses hydraulic actuators, the robot still uses gears. And</p>

<ul>
<li>it is possible to have backlash if you use hydraulic actuators.</li>
<li>And the backlash means any looseness between meshing gears</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>4.ATLAS robot27 joints are rotational.</p>

<ul>
<li>And they use position control, torque control and PID control.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>5.ATLAS arms have 7 DOF. This means that manipulator is redundant.</p>

<ul>
<li>The controllable degrees of freedom > total degrees of freedom</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>6.Hands and feet are the end-effectors of the robot.</p></li>
<li><p>7.drive:</p>

<ul>
<li>ATLAS need to detect depth through vision. Is stereopsis desired? True</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>8.In order to ATLAS to be able to detect LANES on a road, Edge detection might be most useful</p></li>
<li><p>9.walk:</p>

<ul>
<li>if one leg (angle, knee and hip) has 4 DOF, and four PID controller needs to control the motion of the leg.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>10.clear the way</p>

<ul>
<li>compliance would not be beneficial in removing blocks to protect the robot from being hurt.</li>
<li>Torque control is the control method used to grab the door handle firmly</li>
<li>When open a door, we can choose Robustness to optimize path planning trajectories.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>11.climb ladder</p>

<ul>
<li>In order for robots to be successful in the real world they need to deal with uncertainty.</li>
<li>Programming robots to do the same thing over and over does not work in real environments. Instead they need to be able to generalize.</li>
<li>In the scenario, there are multiple ways in which ATLAS could coordinate the motion between his arms and legs. One coordination scheme for climbing could be the alternating gait(the way of walking)</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>12.pip detection</p>

<ul>
<li>Laser-range scanner to compute distance is the most useful in helping the robot move through the building and find the leaking pipe</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>13.valve closing</p>

<ul>
<li>In the scenario the robot is using a P controller on each of the arm joint to control how much the joint should move, during experimental results it was shown that controller showed large oscillatory behavior during the initial motion the hand.

<ul>
<li>PD Controller would do a better job at eliminating such error</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>After the controller is changed, the oscillatory behavior disappeared. But now the controller war not eliminating the steady-state error effectively

<ul>
<li>PID controller would do a better job at eliminating the current and previous error</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>14.type of sensor</p>

<ul>
<li>cameras is a Exteroceptive sensor</li>
<li>robot need dynamic stability to maintain the balance.</li>
<li>Encode sensor can detect the position of its joints through this kind of sensor</li>
<li>Tactile sensor can detect touching object</li>
<li>ATLAS is not equip with Bump sensor</li>
<li>The force torque sensors give internal information of the robot state(Proprioceptive)</li>
<li>In some parts of the task, we want ATLAS not to be compliant but to be? Stiff</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2013 IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Biomimetics]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2014/04/09/2013-ieee-international-conference-on-robotics-and-biomimetics/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-09T13:08:03+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2014/04/09/2013-ieee-international-conference-on-robotics-and-biomimetics</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<pre><code>Dec 12-14 2013 shenzhen, China
</code></pre>

<h4>Team members</h4>

<pre><code>pengbin
qiudicong
zhudingqiao
</code></pre>

<h4>here are the picture</h4>

<p><img src="/images/ieee1.jpg">
<img src="/images/ieee2.jpg">
<img src="/images/ieee3.jpg"></p>

<!--more-->


<h4>Stable Reflex-based walking of forelimbs of a Bio-inspired Quadruped Robot-Modeled Cheetah</h4>

<pre><code>Osaka(大阪大学)
Shogo Nakatsu
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>talk about reflex-based control</li>
<li>something like create muscle activity pattern through biographical electric</li>
<li>it can react 80cm/s</li>
<li>this is about a four legs robot</li>
</ul>


<h4>one of the researchers</h4>

<pre><code>first one 
name:Kottaeuser
paderborn
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>focusing in 3D vision</li>
<li>some laser-based</li>
<li>some measurement</li>
</ul>


<h4>first interview of the researcher</h4>

<pre><code>name:C.de Chambrier
live and work in Switzerland
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>And here are the answer to the four questions(<code>The answer are from the speaker not me~~~ and I make it seems like an interview to show you</code>):

<ul>
<li><strong>What are you major?</strong>

<ul>
<li>I am focusing on the AI algorithm and the strategy.</li>
<li>that is to say I am major in the higher level of the robotics.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How do you get interested in robotics?</strong>

<ul>
<li>when I am in master&rsquo;s degree, I am interested in robot</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>What impressed you most?</strong>

<ul>
<li>I am really interested in the strategy design and algorithm design of the robots.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>what do you think about the robot will change the world in the next 10 years?</strong>

<ul>
<li>I have three point of view about what the robot is going to be in the next decade.</li>
<li>first of all

<ul>
<li>Automatic cars(like google smart car), is going to develop well to drive themselves. and they will be able to work without human affection. But due to the law, they may not be able to get on the road everywhere.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>secondly

<ul>
<li>home service robot is to be well developed. But they may be designed for specific task. Not just to make it human like.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>thirdly

<ul>
<li>human-like robot are kinds of wired, because human may alloy emotional association with those robots that looks like a human. And well-designed human-like robot may still need a long time to proceed.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>What are the biggest problems that YOU think robotics can solve in our generation?</strong>

<ul>
<li>I think that the materials are going to be the barrier to come over.</li>
<li>Currently, we have to use big actuators and movement which can not be smooth. The energy cost is high that a mobile robot has to carry a big battery, and yet the energy runs out so quickly. Hence, new materials that provide actions like a human body and in low energy cost are required for the future development of robotics.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>second interview</h4>

<pre><code> a lecturer
 name:Inaki Rano
 from UK university of UIster
 have worked 6  years 
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>talk about Direct collocation for two dimensional motion camoutflage with non-holonomic, velocity and acceleration constraints</li>
<li><strong>The movement of the human&rsquo;s hand between two location is always on a 3D plane, and he wanted to applied this phenomenon in object moving or obstacle-avoidance tasks for a grasping robot. He had mathematically proved a strong-related theory about this phenomenon</strong></li>
<li>And here are the answer to the four questions(<code>The answer are from the speaker not me~~~ and I make it seems like an interview to show you</code>):

<ul>
<li><strong>What are you major?</strong>

<ul>
<li>all kind of fields in the robotics</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How do you get interested in robotics?</strong>

<ul>
<li>when I am in college, I am interested in robot</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>What impressed you most?</strong>

<ul>
<li>everything in the robot</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>what do you think about the robot will change the world in the next 10 years?</strong>

<ul>
<li>The robot may be very common in the future life and every one will notice it</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>What are the biggest problems that YOU think robotics can solve in our generation?</strong>

<ul>
<li>The Model that use to the robot may be one of the most difficult part in the robotics.</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>a researcher talk about using a smart phone to connect the Robot</h4>

<pre><code>a girl from China State Key lab of Robotics and System
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>focusing in the protocol design</li>
</ul>


<h4>Direct and indirect social robot interactions in a hotel public space</h4>

<pre><code>a japanese researcher from Tsukuba(筑波大学)
name：潘雅冬
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>talk about the social robot that react in the hotel</li>
<li>and he talk about three patterns

<ul>
<li>passing</li>
<li>looking</li>
<li>staying and approaching</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>using 3 kinds of robot(human-like)

<ul>
<li>NAO</li>
<li>Gemini</li>
<li>Palro</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>use kinect: Methodology

<ul>
<li>presence</li>
<li>position</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>南开大学教授</h4>

<pre><code>段峰博士
建立系统，一种synchronous and control system
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>also develop some kinect app on the nap robot</li>
</ul>


<h4>third interview</h4>

<pre><code>name:Yujin Wakita
work in AIST( The National Institute of Advanced Industrial Science and Technology)
have participate in robotic for 23 years
focus in UI(人机交互)
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>application:

<ul>
<li>mobile assist</li>
<li>parking</li>
<li>power system of nurse</li>
<li>toilet robot</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>And here are the answer to the four questions(<code>The answer are from the speaker not me~~~, and I make it seems like an interview to show you</code>):

<ul>
<li><strong>What are you major?</strong>

<ul>
<li>user interface, human assistance</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>How do you get interested in robotics?</strong>

<ul>
<li>when I am in high school, I am interested in robot</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>What impressed you most?</strong>

<ul>
<li>the robot that can assist human</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>what do you think about the robot will change the world in the next 10 years?</strong>

<ul>
<li>It is hard to say.Lots of designs and ideas are occurring. And it is hard to tell whether the assistance robots may develop towards human-like or functionally specialized.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>What are the biggest problems that YOU think robotics can solve in our generation?</strong>

<ul>
<li>the social problem that may cost by the robot</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>Geometric balancing control of humanoid robots</h4>

<pre><code>LaSabana university
name:Mario Arbulu
</code></pre>

<ul>
<li>societal side</li>
<li>front side</li>
<li>use attitude sensor</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
