<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: UML | KING]]></title>
  <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/categories/uml/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-04-20T13:17:42+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://pbking1.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[pb]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[10 Uml Homework of System Analyze and Design]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2014/04/20/10-uml-homework-of-system-analyze-and-design/"/>
    <updated>2014-04-20T12:57:18+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2014/04/20/10-uml-homework-of-system-analyze-and-design</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>1. 概念类图（Conceptual Class Diagram / Domian Model）</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>实验目的：</p>

<ul>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握概念类图的涵义和内容</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握概念类图的绘制方法</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握概念类图的使用范围</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>实验内容：</p></li>
<li><ol>
<li>Read the game description of &ldquo;Priests and Devils&rdquo; .</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><p>Priests and Devils
  Priests and Devils is a puzzle game in which you will help the Priests and Devils to cross the river within the time limit. There are 3 priests and 3 devils at one side of the river. They all want to get to the other side of this river, but there is only one boat and this boat can only carry two persons each time. And there must be one person steering the boat from one side to the other side. In the flash game, you can click on them to move them and click the go button to move the boat to the other direction. If the priests are out numbered by the devils on either side of the river, they get killed and the game is over. You can try it in many ways. Keep all priests alive! Good luck!</p></li>
<li><p>and play the game ( <a href="http://www.flash-game.net/game/2535/priests-and-devils.html">http://www.flash-game.net/game/2535/priests-and-devils.html</a> ) first.</p></li>
<li><ol>
<li>识别游戏中出现的概念，并画出概念类图。要求给出类、属性、以及类之间的关联（建议有多重性）。</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>首先概念类图就是领域模型,是对领域内的概念类或者现实世界 对象的可视化表示。并且领域模型并不是对软件对象的描述,他是现 实世界领域中的概念和想象可视化。他不需要方法。</li>
<li>其次是设计领域模型的步骤。</li>
<li>首先从业务中抽取名词,然后从提取出来的名词中中总结业务实 体,区分名词汇中的属性,角色,实体和实例,形成问题域中的操作 实体的集合。其次是从业务实体集合中抽象业务模型,简历问题域的 概念。最后是用 UML 提供的方法和图例进行领域模型的设计,确定 模型之间的关系。</li>
<li>因此我们可以从文本中抽取出包含的类 Priest, Devil, puzzleGame, River, RiverSide, Boat, 另外还有 Player, Clock 类。
<img src="/images/hw1.jpg"></li>
</ul>


<h3>2. 活动图（Activity Diagram）</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>实验目的：</p>

<ul>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握活动图的涵义和内容</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握活动图的绘制方法</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握活动图的使用范围</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>实验内容：</p>

<ul>
<li><ol>
<li>选择你熟悉银行的ATM机器，仔细研究观察“人”“机器”对话交互，实现取钱功能的过程。</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>用活动图画出用户取钱的过程。</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>解题思路

<ul>
<li><ol>
<li>活动图</li>
<li>活动图是UML用于对系统的动态行为建模的另外一种常用工具，他描述活动的顺序展现从一个活动到另外一个活动的控制流。活动图的本质上是一种流程图。</li>
<li>活动图着重表现从一个活动到另外一个活动的控制流。</li>
<li>也表示一个过程中的多个顺序活动和并行活动。</li>
<li>一旦某个动作完成，紧接着或有一个自动的向外转换。面向对象，着重表现系统的行为而不是处理的顺序。</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>简单的控制流图包含操作，控制流，初始节点，活动最终节点，决策节点，合并节点，注释</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>本体的信息如下</li>
<li>活动主体：用户 ATM机，银行</li>
<li>大致流程：插卡，输入密码，输入取款金额，取款，取卡</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p><img src="/images/hw2.jpg"></p>

<h3>3. 状态机图（State Machine Diagram）</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>实验目的：</p>

<ul>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握状态机图的涵义和内容</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握状态机图的绘制方法</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>掌握状态机图的使用范围</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>实验内容：</p></li>
<li><ol>
<li>Read the material of &ldquo;simple digital watch&rdquo;</li>
<li>simple digital watch</li>
<li>A simple digital watch has a display and two buttons to set it, the A button and the B button. The watch has two modes of operation, display time and set time. In the display time mode, hours and minutes are displayed, separated by a flashing colon.
The set time mode has two sub-modes, set hours and set minutes. The A button is used to select modes. Each time A is pressed, the mode advances in sequence: display, set hours, set minutes, display etc. Within the sub-modes, the B button is used to advance the hours or minutes once each time it is pressed. Buttons must be released before they can generate another event.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>Prepare a state diagram of the watch.</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li>解题思路

<ul>
<li><ol>
<li>状态机图</li>
<li>状态机图显示了对象的生命周期：对象经历的时间，对象的转换和对象在这些时间之间的状态。</li>
<li>而且不需要描述所有可能的时间，只需要为具有复杂行为的依赖对象简历状态机图就可以了。</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>状态机图的组件</li>
<li>事件，状态和转换</li>
</ol>
</li>
<li><ol>
<li>题目解析</li>
<li>题意翻译如下：

<ul>
<li>有一块电子表，有显示模式，设置时间模式（分为小时和分钟两种子模式），A按钮切换模式，B按钮则是在设置模式下调整时间，按钮不能同时按下去。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ol>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>则很容易得出状态机图为
<img src="/images/hw3.jpg"></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
