<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: economic | KING]]></title>
  <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/categories/economic/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-01T14:28:39-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://pbking1.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[pb]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[CLEP microeconomic practise exam]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/28/clep-microeconomic-practise-exam/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-28T15:03:29-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/28/clep-microeconomic-practise-exam</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>exam 1</h3>

<ul>
<li>1.If a producing firm does not have enough time to expand its plant capacity生产规模, it is:

<ul>
<li><strong>operating in the short run</strong></li>
<li>因为没时间，所以要赶紧做事，以免被别人打败

<ul>
<li>所以只能进行短期运营</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>2.Economic costs of production differ from accounting costs of production in that:

<ul>
<li><strong>economic costs add the opportunity cost of a firm using its own resources.</strong></li>
<li>经济利润和会计利润

<ul>
<li>会计利润：总收入减总成本</li>
<li>经济利润：总收入减总成本减机会成本</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>3.An example of a long run adjustment is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Walmart builds another Supercenter.</strong></li>
<li>长期运营的话就要扩大规模</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>4.The reason the marginal product of labor in the short run increases at first and then falls is because:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>there are fewer opportunities for division of labor and specialization.</strong></li>
<li>边际产量：增加一个劳动力增加的产量</li>
<li>边际产量递减规律

<ul>
<li>边际产量递减，所以边际成本递增</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>一开始效果明显，到后来基数大了所以就不明显了

<ul>
<li>工人少，人数增加效率增加</li>
<li>工人越多，就会存在协调问题，所以效率就会下降</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>5.If 11 workers can produce a total of 54 units of a product and another worker has a marginal product of six, then the average product of 12 workers is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>(54 + 6)/12 = 5</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>6.Economies of scale exist because as a firm increases its size in the long run:</p>

<ul>
<li> <strong>labor and management can specialize their activities more.</strong>    &ndash;  <strong>as a larger input buyer the firm can purchase inputs at a lower per unit cost.</strong>    &ndash; <strong>the firm can afford more sophisticated technology in production.</strong>    &ndash; 规模经济：        &ndash; 固定成本：器材（本来就有的）            &ndash; 固有资产        &ndash; 可变成本：劳动力（可以增加可以减少）            &ndash; 会随着产量变动而变动的成本

<ul>
<li>平均固定成本：固有资产平均分到课本成本上

<ul>
<li>随着产量的增加，递减的</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>平均可变成本：例如原材料

<ul>
<li>随着产量的增加，递增的</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>平均总成本：平均可变成本 + 平均固定成本

<ul>
<li></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>7.In natural monopolies such as the generation of electricity, long-run average costs continue to decrease as the plant size gets larger, because:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>diseconomies of scale are very minor but economies of scale continue.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>8.In figure 10.2, the difference between average total costs and average variable costs is:</p></li>
<li><img src="/images/econ/1.png" alt="Image" /></li>
<li><img src="/images/econ/">

<ul>
<li><strong>average fixed costs.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>9.In figure 10.2, average variable costs approach average total costs as output rises because:

<ul>
<li><strong>average fixed costs are falling.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>10.In figure 10.2, when marginal costs are rising:

<ul>
<li><strong>marginal product of labor is declining.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>11.Both individual buyers and sellers in perfect competition:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>have to take the market price as a given.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>12.If a perfectly competitive seller is producing at an output where price is $11 and the marginal cost is $14.54, then to maximise profits the firm should:</p>

<ul>
<li> <strong>produce a smaller level of output.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>13.A very large number of small sellers who sell identical products implies:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>the inability of one seller to influence price.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><img src="/images/econ/2.png" alt="Image" /></p></li>
<li><img src="/images/econ/"></li>
<li><p>14.At price P1, the firm in figure 11.1 would produce:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>zero</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>15.At price P2, the firm in figure 11.1 would produce:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Q5</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>16.At price P1, the firm in figure 11.1 would:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>lose fixed costs.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>17.At price P3, the firm in figure 11.1 would:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>break down</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>18.At price P4 in the long run, the industry including the firm in figure 11.1 would:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>have entry of new firms.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>19.At price P2 in the long run, the industry including the firm in figure 11.1 would:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>have exit of some existing firms.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>20.When a competitive firm finds that the market price is below its minimum average variable cost level, it will sell:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>nothing at all, the firm shuts down.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>21.If, as the industry expands, a competitive industry can supply larger quantities at the same long-run market price, it is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>a constant-cost industry.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>22.A local electricity-generating company has a monopoly that is protected by a barrier to entry that takes the form of:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>economies of scale.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><img src="/images/econ/3.png" alt="Image" /></p></li>
<li><img src="/images/econ/"></li>
<li><p>23.To profit maximize the firm in figure 14.1 will produce:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Q2</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>24.The profit maximize price for the firm in figure 14.1 is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>P3</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>25.If average total costs are ATC1, the firm in figure 14.1 will:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>make a profit</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>26.In figure 14.1, the difference between the monopoly output and the competitive output is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Q3-Q2</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>27.A profit maximizing monopolistʹs price is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>greater than what the price would be if the mononoplistʹs industry were competitive.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>28.The important economic concept illustrated by increasing opportunity costs is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>the more resources devoted to any activity, the smaller the payoff of devoting more resources to that activity.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>29.A production possibilities frontier model shows that:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>if all resources are fully and efficiently utilized, more output of good X can only be achieved by producing less of another good.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>30.If George can mow 10 lawns or cultivate 5 gardens a day while Jack can mow 6 lawns or cultivate 4 gardens a day, then:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Jack has a comparative advantage in lawn mowing.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>31.If last year the Ajax firm sold 250 sofas at $1,000 each and this year Ajax sold 500 sofas at $1,500 each, then</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>the demand for sofas increased.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>32.The demand for big screen TVs would fall, if big screen TVs are normal goods and:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>buyerʹs of big screen TVs incomes fall because of a recession萧条.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>33.A change in demand represents a <strong><strong><strong><strong> while a change in quantity demanded is a </strong></strong></strong></strong>.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>shift to a new demand curve</strong>; <strong>movement along one demand curve</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>34.If the demand for a good increases when there is high unemployment, we can conclude that the commodity is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>an inferior下级 good</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>35.An advance in technology increases supply:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>because laborʹs or capitalʹs productivity increases and costs of production fall.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>36.When a strike at a major local employer occurs, the demand for television sets in that local market will:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>decreases because buyers incomes have decreased.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>37.If the current market price for a particular book is $30 a unit and a price ceiling is imposed at $20 per book, then:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>there will an increase in the quantity demanded of the book.</strong></li>
<li><strong>a shortage of the book will develop at the ceiling price.</strong>    &ndash; <strong>a price of $20 per book is the legally allowed maximum price of the book.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>38.Among the impacts of the minimum wage工资 is that:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>higher costs are imposed on employers.</strong>    &ndash; <strong>employers substitute other lower cost inputs in place of higher priced labor.</strong>     &ndash; <strong>higher product prices result because production costs are increased.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>39.After a city imposes a rent control law:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>landlords reduce the quantity of apartments offered for rent.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>40.Consumers pay 100% of a new sales tax on a good:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>when the demand is perfectly inelastic.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>41.Which of the following statements about elasticity of demand is correct?</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Demand is more elastic in a long time period than it is in a short time period.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>42.Which of the following goods would most likely have the most inelastic demand?</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>Bread</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>43.If at a price of $100, 10 units were sold while at a price of $125, eight units were sold, the price elasticity of demand value using the midpoint formula is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>one</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>44.If at a price of $50, 20 units are sold and at a price of $60, 0 units are sold, the price elasticity of demand of the good is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>perfectly elastic.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>45.When demand is price elastic, a fall in price causes total revenue to rise because:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>the increase in quantity sold is large enough to offset the lower price.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>46.If the cross-price elasticity of demand for goods A and B is a positive value, this means the two goods are:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>substitutes</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>47.If you expect the economy is going to boom and average income in the economy will rise in the foreseeable future, the type of firm that would be able to increase its sales if your expectations aremet is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>one that sells a luxury good.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>48.An external cost is created when you:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>litter on the side of the road.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>49.Because producers do not bear the external cost of pollution:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>production is beyond the economically efficient level.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p><img src="/images/econ/4.png" alt="Image of Yaktocat" /></p></li>
<li><img src="/images/econ/"></li>
<li>50.An efficient way to get the firm in figure 5.1 to produce what society wants is:

<ul>
<li><strong>a tax to make the firm realize the external costs it imposes on others.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h3>exam 2</h3>

<ul>
<li><p>1.Ex-President Carter’s recommendation of registering women for the draft raised an uproar around the country. One opponent of this proposal stated: &ldquo;Women are needed at home to rear the children, let the men fight the wars.&rdquo; This opponent implied that:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>the opportunity cost associated with drafting women is higher than the opportunity cost of drafting men.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>2.Which of the following accurately describes the fundamental problem at the core of all economic analysis? The fundamental problem is:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>understanding how scarce resources are allocated among competing uses to best satisfy society’s unlimited wants.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>3.If an individual’s demand for frozen dinners increases when the price of steak rises, we would infer that:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>steak and frozen dinners are substitutes for this person</strong>.</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>4.On the New York Stock Exchange, the current price per share for stock of the Boston Celtics, a NBA basketball team, is $8.25. At that price the total quantity of shares demanded is 2,500, while the total quantity supplied for trade is 2,000. It follows that</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>there is a shortage of shares of the Boston Celtics on the stock exchange.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>6.Suppose a political candidate in the upcoming November elections promises voters more funding for AIDS research and child care, and assures them they will not have to sacrifice any other goods or services to obtain the additional programs.</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>This may be possible if the economy has unemployed resources.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>7.This year the demand for new homes increases while at the same time the supply also increases. As a result of these changes in the market for new homes you can conclude that:</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>the equilibrium number of new homes will increase.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>8.Some time ago the government of China required many highly skilled technicians and scientists to engage in unskilled agricultural labor in order to develop &ldquo;proper social attitudes.&rdquo; This policy caused China to produce</p>

<ul>
<li><strong>inside its PPF.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>9.Recent health studies claim that consuming a glass of wine with afternoon or evening meals significantly reduces the risk of heart disease. If people believe this new information, what is likely to occur to the short-run equilibrium in the wine market?
  &ndash;<strong> Equilibrium price and quantity will both rise due to an increase in the demand for wine.</strong></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intro_to_microeconomic_8]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-8/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-08T22:02:14-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-8</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>goal part8</h3>

<ul>
<li>C.Public policy to promote competition

<ul>
<li>1.Antitrust policy</li>
<li>2.Regulation</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>D.Income distribution

<ul>
<li>1.Equity</li>
<li>2.Sources of income ineqiality</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>C.Public policy to promote competition 促进市场竞争的政策

<ul>
<li>1.Antitrust policy

<ul>
<li>反托拉斯法能促进竞争，了解就行</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2.Regulation 政府对垄断的管制

<ul>
<li>如果政府给垄断、垄断竞争、完全竞争企业一次性补贴或一次性征税（lump sum subsidy or tax），不会对企业的MC产生影响，因此不会影响利润最大化产量和价格。</li>
<li>但由于影响了ATC，导致利润或loss有变化。如果征税或补贴是按单位per unit，则会影响MC，继而影响利润最大化产量和价格。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>D.Income distribution 收入分配

<ul>
<li>1.Equity

<ul>
<li>收入不平等的来源：歧视，教育程度不同，能力不同，动机不同。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2.Sources of income ineqiality

<ul>
<li>收入不平等的来源</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intro_to_microeconomic_7]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-7/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-08T22:02:10-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-7</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>goal part7</h3>

<ul>
<li>Market Failure and the Role of Government (12%–18%)

<ul>
<li>A.Externalities

<ul>
<li>1.Marginal social benefit and marginal social cost</li>
<li>2.Positive Externalities</li>
<li>3.Negative externalities</li>
<li>4.Remedies</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>B.Publicgoods

<ul>
<li>1.Public versus private goods</li>
<li>2.Provision of public goods</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>Market Failure and the Role of Government 市场失灵和政府管制

<ul>
<li>A.Externalities外部性

<ul>
<li>1.Marginal social benefit and marginal social cost

<ul>
<li>有外部性的经济活动会产生边际社会收益和边际社会成本</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2.Positive Externalities

<ul>
<li>正外部性：市场生产的数量&lt;社会最优的数量，MSB>MSC</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>3.Negative externalities

<ul>
<li>负外部性：市场生产的数量>社会最优的数量，MSB&lt;MSC</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>4.Remedies

<ul>
<li>对外部性的补救办法：对有负外部性的物品征税，对有正外部性的物品补贴</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>B.Publicgoods

<ul>
<li>1.Public versus private goods

<ul>
<li>私人物品有排他性和竞争性</li>
<li>公共物品没有排他性没有竞争性s</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2.Provision of public goods

<ul>
<li>公共物品的供给：政府收税，统一提供，如国防。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intro_to_microeconomic_6]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-6/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-08T22:02:06-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-6</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>goal part6</h3>

<ul>
<li>Factor Markets (10%–18%)

<ul>
<li>A.Derived factor demand</li>
<li>B.Marginal revenue product</li>
<li>C.Labor market and firms’ hiring of labor</li>
<li>D.Market distribution of income</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li>Factor Markets  要素市场

<ul>
<li>学习时可以类比产品市场的供求均衡</li>
<li>A.Derived factor demand

<ul>
<li>派生需求，概念而已</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>B.Marginal revenue product

<ul>
<li>边际产量值：增加一单位劳力所引起的产值的变化 MRP=P*MP</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>C.Labor market and firms’ hiring of labor

<ul>
<li>劳动需求曲线=MRP曲线，MRP=P<em>MPL，利润最大化雇用人数：w=MRP=P</em>MP</li>
<li>A)影响需求

<ul>
<li>Price的变动，影响MRP，即需求曲线移动</li>
<li>Technological Change技术变革：技术进步—>MP增加——>MRP增加——>需求增加</li>
<li>Supply of Other factors如果企业有更多的设备（资本），劳力的MP会提高</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>B)影响供给

<ul>
<li>Changes in Tastes 女性从家庭中走出；啃老族增加</li>
<li>Changes in other opportunities类似产品市场供给的“substitution”，金融行业吸引人，没人做工程师了……</li>
<li>Immigration 类似产品市场供给的“number of sellers”</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>D.Market distribution of income</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Intro_to_microeconomic_5]]></title>
    <link href="http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-5/"/>
    <updated>2015-02-08T22:02:03-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://pbking1.github.com/blog/2015/02/08/intro-to-microeconomic-5</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3>goal part5</h3>

<ul>
<li>Firm behavior and market structure (25%–35%)

<ul>
<li>1.Profit:

<ul>
<li>a.Accounting versus economic profits</li>
<li>b.Normal profit</li>
<li>c.Profit maximization: MR=MC rule</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>2.Perfect competition

<ul>
<li>a.Profit maximization</li>
<li>b.Short-run supply and shut-down decision</li>
<li>c.Firm and market behaviors in short-run and long-run equilibria</li>
<li>d.Efficiency and perfect competition</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>3.Monopoly

<ul>
<li>a.Sources of market power</li>
<li>b.Profit maximization</li>
<li>c.Inefficiency of monopoly</li>
<li>d.Price discrimination</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>4.Oligopoly

<ul>
<li>a.Interdependence, collusion and cartels</li>
<li>b.Game theory and strategic behavior</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>5.Monopolistic competition

<ul>
<li>a.Product differentiation and role of advertising</li>
<li>b.Profit maximization</li>
<li>c.Short-run and long-run equilibrium</li>
<li>d.Excess capacity and inefficiency</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<!--more-->


<ul>
<li><p>1.Profit:</p>

<ul>
<li><p> a.Accounting versus economic profits</p>

<ul>
<li> 企业都是最求利益最大化的</li>
<li> 会计利润 = 总收益 &ndash; 显性成本</li>
<li> 经济利润 = 显性成本 &ndash; 隐性成本</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p> b.Normal profit</p>

<ul>
<li> 经济利润为0</li>
<li> 但是会计利润不为0</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>c.Profit maximization: MR=MC rule

<ul>
<li>当MR = MC时，利润最大化</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>2.Perfect competition完全竞争</p>

<ul>
<li>特点：有许多买者与卖者，每个企业都无法影响市场价格，是price-taker，因此企业需求曲线是水平的完全弹性的，市场需求曲线向右下方倾斜；进入退出无壁垒，企业在长期无经济利润，因为有利润或损失的话就会有进入或退出直到把利润清零。</li>
<li>a.Profit maximization

<ul>
<li>P=AR是恒等式，因为P=TR/Q,AR=TR/Q。完全竞争市场很特别，企业获得利润最大化的产量是在P=MC=MR=AR时。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>b.Short-run supply and shut-down decision

<ul>
<li>短期的企业供给曲线是MC曲线在AVC上方的那段；在短期，如果P&lt;AVC，企业选择停业；市场长期供给曲线是水平的。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>c.Firm and market behaviors in short-run and long-run equilibria

<ul>
<li>窍门：单个企业和整个市场的供求成本图相互对应。因为企业是价格接受者，所以企业的价格线应与市场的一致。当市场需求有变化从而影响市场均衡价格，再反映到企业的价格变化，企业就有了短期利润或损失，吸引新企业进入市场或导致旧企业退出，从而反映到市场供给曲线往右或往左移动，进而形成新的市场均衡价格，反复调整后，长期均衡价格会等于minATC，而此时刚好也等于MC。        &ndash; 计算短期profit或loss时，应找准P和ATC，Profit=TR-TC=(P-ATC)*Q</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>d.Efficiency and perfect competition

<ul>
<li>因为P=MC，所以完全竞争市场有效率。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>3.Monopoly垄断</p>

<ul>
<li>特点：只有一家企业，因此需求曲线向右下方倾斜；自己定价，是price maker；有壁垒，因此有长期经济利润</li>
<li>a.Sources of market power

<ul>
<li>垄断的三种来源：天然拥有某种资源，如南非钻石；政府给予的特权，如专利保护；自然垄断，由规模经济引起的，如供电。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>b.Profit maximization利益最大化

<ul>
<li>先通过MR=MC的条件确定产量Q，再通过需求曲线找到对应的P，这是垄断企业利润最大化的条件。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>c.Inefficiency of monopoly 垄断无效率

<ul>
<li>因为产量少于需求并且收取高于期望的价格，所以垄断是效率低的。too little of the production and charges too high a price</li>
<li>P=AR>MR</li>
<li>会画图。知道Revenue maximizing（MR=0的产量），profit maximizing（MR=MC）, efficient maximizing（P=MC）与fair return企业经济利润为0（ATC和D相交）这四种情况下的产量和价格。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>d.Price discrimination价格歧视

<ul>
<li>对每个消费者收取不同的价格，MR曲线与D重合，把所有消费者剩余都剥夺过来变成企业自己的利润。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>4.Oligopoly 寡头</p>

<ul>
<li>a.Interdependence, collusion and cartels卡特尔、联盟、互赖

<ul>
<li> 受反托拉斯法的约束，有market power，企业数量很少；合作的话，如同垄断一般获利最大，如果不合作，则利润不高。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>b.Game theory and strategic behavior博弈论和占优策略

<ul>
<li> 会利用支付矩阵分析占优策略。题目中可能一方有占优策略另一方无占优策略，那么没有的那方要先揣测出有占优的那方的意图。</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><p>5.Monopolistic competition垄断竞争</p>

<ul>
<li>a.Product differentiation and role of advertising

<ul>
<li> 有许多卖者，每个卖者提供略有差别的产品，无壁垒，有决定价格的能力，做广告的必要性</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>b.Profit maximisation

<ul>
<li>P=AR>MR</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>c.Short-run and long-run equilibrium

<ul>
<li>短期有profit或loss，吸引新企业进入或旧企业退出市场。</li>
<li>进而达到长期均衡，D与ATC曲线相切，切点刚好是MC=MR投影到D的点，长期利润为0。因为在ATC的下降部分相切，所以有规模经济。</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li>d.Excess capacity and inefficiency

<ul>
<li>垄断竞争无效率体现在：产能过剩 Excess capacity，价格过高 P>MC</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<h4>exercise</h4>

<ul>
<li>1.What is the connection between elasticity and total revenue?

<ul>
<li><strong>elasticity弹性 and total revenue总收益 are related</strong>

<ul>
<li><strong>if a good is elastic in demand, total revenue will increase(decrease) with a price decrease(increase).</strong></li>
<li>2.Explain why the short-run demand curve is usually less elastic than the long-run demand curve?</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>题意为：为什么短期需求曲线比长期需求曲线更加没弹性。</strong></li>
<li><p><strong>因为你在长期需求是有更多时间来决策，因此会增加你的选择可能性。并且增加需求弹性</strong></p></li>
<li><p>3.Which item in each pair has the larger elasticity of demand? Why?    &ndash; a. <strong>Sports Illustrated</strong> or a magazine    &ndash; b.Vacations or <strong>vacations in Cancun</strong>    &ndash; c.<strong>Broccoli</strong> or vegetables    &ndash; d.<strong>An IUPUI education</strong> or a college education</p></li>
<li>4.Define income elasticity of demand and cross-elasticity of demand.</li>
<li><strong>Income elasticity of demand:</strong>

<ul>
<li><strong>the percentage change in quantity demanded for a given percentage change in income.</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><strong>cross-elasticity of demand:</strong>

<ul>
<li><strong>the percentage change in the demand for good x when there is a given %change in the price of good y</strong>&ndash; 5.What are the differences between momentary, short-run, and long-run supply? Which is the most elastic? The least elastic?     &ndash; <strong>long run supply is the most elastic in demand, monetary货币 is the least elastic in demand</strong></li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
